# 真正炸酱面还是在北京
The real pork noodles with soybean paste are only available in Beijing
# 它没有标准
There is no standard
# 是所有人都会做
Every Beijinger can make it
# 就每个家每个家庭
Every family
# 都做的手法不一样
They all have their own versions
# 但是你去谁家吃都好吃
But every single of them is tasty
# 这是什么 摄像机
What’s this? It’s a camera
# 这就是炸酱面的码
These are the toppings for the noodles
# 八个码什么码都可以
Eight kinds of toppings or whatever you like
# 不是这白菜太脆了
These Chinese cabbages are so crunchy
# 跟咱们北京的白菜不太一样
They are different from what we have in Beijing
# 它的水比较大
They are quite watery
# 北京黄酱多香啊
This soybean paste is so aromatic
# 澥成这样你看
Dilute with water until it looks like this
# 跟我围裙一样也是这样戴的
I wear my apron this way as well
# 老北京的炸酱面油要大
You need a large amount of oil
# 愿意吃块儿大的
Everyone loves big pieces
# 八角就是大料
Star anise is an essential ingredient
# 你得把那油脱脂脱出来
You must render the fat out
# 把那肉稍微要有焦感
Pork pieces should be slightly brown and crispy
# 它才会有焦香味 对
So they can develop that fragrance from caramelisation
# 到这份上就可以了
It’s right on spot now
# 下酱不能全下去
You can’t pour all paste in at once
# 一边炒一边下
You must add it in batches
# 就都能把酱炸透了
So it can be thoroughly fried
# 你如果一倒进去就咕嘟了
If you pour all of the paste into the pan, it will become boiled
# 做饭手法很重要 程序
The steps in cooking are important (or procedures)
# 很多人为什么味道会差一点
A lot of dishes are not as tasty
# 程序弄错 香味提不出来
Because they messed up the procedures, so the fragrance was not lifted
# 分三次下
Add it in three batches
# 最后剩一点 这个就不能加凉水
For the last bit, you can’t mix it with cold water
# 因为它会降温
Because it will cause the temperature to drop
# 在这个过程中就可以提一点糖
Add in a little bit of sugar in the meantime
# 充当味精用
It acts like MSG
# 而且糖有个好处
Also, sugar has an extra benefit
# 可以让色泽更漂亮
That it can make the final dish brighter and more colourful
# 就说做什么东西一定要见着物
I always say that you must see the ingredients whenever you cook
# 就见着它的主材
You must see the main ingredients of a dish
# 一搁肉沫就不好吃了这东西很怪
It would be tasteless and weird if you put pork mince in this dish
# 色香味俱全
Now it’s colourful, fragrant and tasty
# 炸酱不要着急
You must be patient when you fry the sauce
# 它是一态度问题
It’s attitude
# 你态度好炸出酱就好
If you are patient, the sauce will be perfect in return
# 你要态度不好着急
On the contrary, if you have a bad temper
# 肉也腥酱也不熟
The meat will be smelly, and the sauce will not be properly cooked
# 前期炒的时候你记住一定用这火
Remember to use such heat when you first fry them
# 慢慢澥慢慢收
Slowly dilute the sauce and then slowly thicken it
# 把肉的油憋出来出来
Render the fat out of the meat
# 然后逼进酱里
And then push it back to the sauce
# 到这时候可以了关小火
Now turn down to low heat
# 慢慢慢慢的㸆
Braise the sauce really slowly
# 这才叫老北京的小碗干炸 知道吧
This is what I call ‘deep fried sauce in small bowls’, you know
# 这酱全裹在肉上
All meat pieces are covered with the sauce
# 这肉块也比我们家大
These meat pieces are bigger than what we usually use
# 对你们家不舍得
Yes, because your family are not willing to spend too much on those things
# 你爸说了过日子讲究一点
Your father always says that you need to be particular about the spending
# 大块吃着多过瘾
It feels so satisfied to eat these big pieces
# 你看老北京有时候搁点香油
Old Beijingers will sometimes add in some sesame oil here
# 一定要有油植物油
There must be oil, vegetable oil
# 我们过去老北京有句话叫什么
We Beijingers had a saying called
# 想长寿吃肥肉
Eat fats if you want to live longer
# 不是肥肉不好 一定要吃肥肉
Fatty meats are not evil, and you must eat them
# 出锅了 好香哦
Take them out of the pan. They smell so good
# 一定是肉是肉(油是油)酱是酱
Meat, oil and paste must be separate like this
# 酱一定裹在肉上 酱得裹肉上
The meat pieces must be covered with the sauce
# 油要凸显出来
Oil needs to stand out
# 不要说酱粘粘乎乎一堆
Don’t make it mixed up altogether
# 这就是小碗干炸
This is the authentic ‘deep fried sauce in small bowls’
# 刚才我们讲的这面开锅点三次水
Dip the noodles in boiling water three times like we just said
# 台湾这个面还真好
These Taiwanese noodles are so good
# 你看又白又筋道
Brilliantly white and chewy
# 咱们吃面的时候先这样
We shall eat the noodles like this
# 它给一勺还要擓一勺油 润它
One spoonful of the sauce with an extra spoon of oil to moisturise the noodles
# 黄瓜丝
Cucumber juliennes
# 芹菜末
Celery cubes
# 豆角白菜
Cowpeas and Chinese cabbage
# 这个码比面多
There should be more toppings than the actual noodles
# 吃的就是码和酱
Toppings and sauce are the centrepiece of this dish
# 萝卜丝 咱北京是心儿里美
Radish juliennes. We Beijingers use this sweet pink-fleshed radish
# 这个您就自己拌 拌透了
You may mix up everything by yourself. Mix them evenly
# 不要怕油
Don’t be afraid of the oil
# 咱讲的是什么 猪油是这样
We have a saying for the pork fat
# 我父亲活了八十七八
My father lived to his late eighties
# 他说了想长寿吃肥肉
He said if you wanted to live longer, you must eat fatty meats
# 然后但是必须要跟上茶
And then drink some tea
# 吃肥肉没事茶跟上
It’s absolutely fine to eat fatty meats as long as you also drink tea
# 这个大蒜真棒来一口
These garlics are fantastic
# 一口面一口大蒜
One mouthful of noodles and one bite of garlics
# 对味的
They match so well
# 这个面条的酱炸到什么叫最好
The best sauce for the noodles is that
# 拌完以后这面条是枣红色
The noodles will become jujube red after mixing up
# 酱红色特别感觉有食欲的
Such red colour lifts the appetite so much
# 给个表示怎么样
What do you think of the dish?
# 武大师亲手做的
Hand made by Shifu Wu
# 比我的亲家做得还好
It tastes even better than my parents-in-law’s version
# 行了充电去吧
Alright guys, give it a go